NIKITA VAVILOV

Turkey, Antalya \(\phi \) nikita@vavilov.io \(\phi \) tg@vavilovns \(\phi \) linkedin/vavilovns

OBJECTIVE

I'm an proficient software engineer with 8+ years of experience. I've participated in almost every stage of the development lifecycle, including support (1st, 2nd, and 3rd lines), maintenance, development (Backend, Frontend, DevOps), architecture, and requirements analysis. Some of my positions have given me experience with management, and I have established effective development processes and improved development culture. My main field is Java, however recently I have mostly been working with Kotlin. I'm always open to all opportunities for working with application architecture.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Aug 2022 - Present

Leroy Merlin (The third company in the world in terms of sales of D.I.Y. goods)

Moscow, Russia

- Reduced manual work on updating and versioning applications by 80% by refining CI/CD pipelines.
- Investigated Camunda 8(bpmn engine) to prove its production readiness by examining throughput, bottlenecks, and the overall stability of the system.

Team Lead

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

X5 Retail Group (The second-largest private company in Russia)

Moscow, Russia

- Stabilized the system, reducing service crashes by 70%, through the improvement of infrastructure-as-code and the establishment of a release cycle.
- Determined the maximum system throughput for scaling to all divisions by reorganizing load testing.

Lead Software Engineer

Aug 2019 - Feb 2022

AMT Group (System integrator)

Moscow, Russia

- Developed an MVP of a system for analyzing the causes of failure of transmitters with a planned load of 2,000 RPS.
- Refined the application of rescue squad by moving the backend functionality to the frontend and adding PWA.

Team Lead

Feb 2017 - Aug 2019

AMT Group (System integrator)

Moscow, Russia

- Shortened the time-to-market from 1-2 months to 1 week by improving the culture of development and auto testing.
- Shortened system downtime during updates from 1 hour to 1 minute by developing a Continuous Delivery system for a proprietary application.

Software Engineer

May 2016 - Feb 2017

AMT Group (System integrator)

Moscow, Russia

- Improved the proprietary system to support async query execution, which allowed avoiding replacing the system.
- Gained a 2x improvement in application performance by developing a system for archiving historical data.

Software Engineer

Sep 2014 - May 2016

Raiffeisen Bank International (One of the largest Austrian banking groups)

Moscow, Russia

- Decreased the processing time of frequent support requests by 15% by integrating information from corporate systems into the operator interface.
- Reduced support calls by 20% by developing a chatbot that provides information on the progress of work requests and knowledge base articles.

SKILLS

Java, Kotlin, Spring, Microservices, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, Kubernetes, Openshift, Jenkins, Gitlab CI, Postgres, SQL Server, GreenPlum, MongoDB

EDUCATION